<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Penny and Alistair</title>
    <link>http://pennyandalistair.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Penny and Alistair</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pennyandalistair.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip planning</title>
      <link>http://pennyandalistair.github.io/trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pennyandalistair.github.io/trip/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-to-the-venue-hotel:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Getting to the venue/hotel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought many people would rent a car - so we&amp;rsquo;ve created a form to facilitate carpooling. You can fill in the form here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/forms/qN5a4t8QptQmC4se2&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/forms/qN5a4t8QptQmC4se2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll get in touch very soon to coordinate you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-around:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Getting around&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are staying within Toronto, then public transportation is your best option as parking tends to be $15 for the day. You can pay for all fares by cash, but a better option is to buy tokens or tickets at a metro stop, as they are cheaper. There&amp;rsquo;s also a new electronic pass thing called &amp;ldquo;Presto&amp;rdquo;, but we&amp;rsquo;ve never used it so we can&amp;rsquo;t comment on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more info at the Toronto Transit Commission (TTC) website:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ttc.ca/Fares_and_passes/Prices/index.jsp&#34;&gt;https://www.ttc.ca/Fares_and_passes/Prices/index.jsp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not staying in Toronto, or in the Greater Toronto Area (GTA), you can consider GO Trains for getting in/out of Toronto, or traveling to cities further away.
You can find maps here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gotransit.com/timetables/en/schedules/maps.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.gotransit.com/timetables/en/schedules/maps.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the GO train into Toronto is usually only worth it for two people. If you have more, parking in Toronto will probably end up being cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inside-toronto:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Inside toronto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is loads to see inside Toronto! Here are some of our personal favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cn-tower:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;CN Tower&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t visit Toronto without also visiting the Canadian National (CN) Tower, the big pointy thing in the middle of the city. I used to call it the tallest tower in the world but that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been true for six years now :( it&amp;rsquo;s still really cool to visit though! You get great views both indoor and outdoor (be warned there is a bit of a breeze), and there is a glass floor to stand on.. if you are brave enough. If you are &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; crazy, you can book an &amp;ldquo;edge walk&amp;rdquo; where they hang you from the side of the building. The downside is it&amp;rsquo;s a bit pricey at $35 to visit the tower for adults. One good tip is that entrance is complimentary if you eat at the &lt;em&gt;360 restaurant&lt;/em&gt; (CN tower) - their two course prix fixe menu is $56 - so you can treat yourself to a fancy meal and feel like you are saving money :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;360 restaurant: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cntower.ca/en-ca/360-restaurant/reservations-and-menus.html&#34;&gt;http://www.cntower.ca/en-ca/360-restaurant/reservations-and-menus.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CN tower info (+ online booking): &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cntower.ca/en-ca/plan-your-visit/attractions/lookout.html&#34;&gt;http://www.cntower.ca/en-ca/plan-your-visit/attractions/lookout.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;baseball-game:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Baseball game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to catch a baseball game, you can do that at the Rogers centre. On the weekend of the wedding (23rd-25th of September) the Blue Jays (Toronto&amp;rsquo;s baseball team) are playing the New York Yankees at home. Blue Jays tickets are available here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://toronto.bluejays.mlb.com/ticketing/singlegame.jsp?c_id=tor&#34;&gt;http://toronto.bluejays.mlb.com/ticketing/singlegame.jsp?c_id=tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;harbourfront-centre:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Harbourfront Centre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Harbourfront Centre is a lakeside area along the south coast of Toronto which hosts regular events. A particularly nice place to walk, you can also visit the Toronto music garden, designed by Yo Yo Ma and Julie Moir Messeervy. The garden has &amp;ldquo;musical&amp;rdquo; tours on Thursdays at 5:30pm and Wednesdays at 11am (45 minutes, led by a volunteer). Details here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.harbourfrontcentre.com/venues/torontomusicgarden/index.cfm#tour&#34;&gt;http://www.harbourfrontcentre.com/venues/torontomusicgarden/index.cfm#tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pennyandalistair.github.io/img/music-garden.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fill-container-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They host concerts regularly during the summer, but unfortunately the last one is the Sunday before our wedding! Still, if you&amp;rsquo;re around, it might be worth a visit!
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.harbourfrontcentre.com/summermusic/performances/&#34;&gt;http://www.harbourfrontcentre.com/summermusic/performances/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;microbreweries:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Microbreweries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canadian microbrewing in Ontario is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; starting to take off, good news for us. Toronto actually has a few breweries within the city that you can try out. If you&amp;rsquo;re in the area of the CN tower or Rogers centre, then you have two good options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steam Whistle&amp;rsquo;s brewery does tours go from 11am to 6pm (5pm on Sunday) and their pilsner is pretty nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://steamwhistle.ca/tour/tourInfo.php&#34;&gt;http://steamwhistle.ca/tour/tourInfo.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you could try Amsterdam Brewery - we are actually serving Amsterdam Cruiser at the wedding so you can see where it&amp;rsquo;s made! They have a brewhouse at 245 Queen&amp;rsquo;s Quay West (right next to the Harbourfront Centre) and you can either eat there from 11am onward (it&amp;rsquo;s a restaurant) or visit for a free tours on Monday/Tuesday 4pm, Wednesday-Sunday 12pm/2pm/4pm/6pm. We both plan on going when we&amp;rsquo;re back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amsterdambrewhouse.com/brewhouse-brewery-tour-registration/&#34;&gt;http://amsterdambrewhouse.com/brewhouse-brewery-tour-registration/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toronto-island:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Toronto Island&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take a ferry from the harbour to islands off the coast of Toronto. The island has a great view of Toronto, an amusement park for kids, and tons of green space for you to stretch your legs. The most popular island is Centre Island but you can visit any of them - if you&amp;rsquo;re really brave there&amp;rsquo;s a nude beach (the only one in Toronto) but if you invite us we&amp;rsquo;ll have to give a rain check.. Ferry info here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.toronto.ca/wps/portal/contentonly?vgnextoid=3690dada600f0410VgnVCM10000071d60f89RCRD&#34;&gt;http://www1.toronto.ca/wps/portal/contentonly?vgnextoid=3690dada600f0410VgnVCM10000071d60f89RCRD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;royal-ontario-museum-rom:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Royal Ontario Museum (ROM)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ROM is a fairly nice museum with some interesting exhibits on (Chihuly, a light display using various colours of sand, is quite interesting). It&amp;rsquo;s also very child friendly with exhibits about dinosaurs and the like (you can take a picture with a CG t-rex). Lots of natural history here. It&amp;rsquo;s a little on the expensive side though, base admission is $17 for adults, $14 for children, and each exhibit is roughly an additional $7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely worth checking out is Summer Fridays, where the museum stays open late (until 8:30 p.m.), has discounted admission after 4:30pm ($10), and live music/shows in the c5 lounge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pennyandalistair.github.io/img/rom-hipsters.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fill-container-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relax and enjoy a drink! Beware though, as you can tell from the picture above, hipsters abound..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;distillery-district:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Distillery district&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distillery district is a historic part of Toronto - it used to be home to (surprise) a distillery - in fact the largest distillery at the time (though this was the 1860s, probably not much competition). The area deindustrialized and in 2000 it was revamped to be a pedestrian oriented area (which feel rare in the big cities). You get an interesting mix of Victorian industrial era buildings with hip cafes and the like - definitely worth a visit!
Read more here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedistillerydistrict.com/index.html&#34;&gt;http://www.thedistillerydistrict.com/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kensington-market:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Kensington market&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting part of Toronto - it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hippy and dodgy but very safe. It&amp;rsquo;s also pedestrianized on Sunday - stop by a cafe here and people watch! Also right next to Chinatown, if you get hungry :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kensington-market.ca/Default.asp?id=getting-to-kensington&amp;amp;l=1&#34;&gt;http://www.kensington-market.ca/Default.asp?id=getting-to-kensington&amp;amp;l=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baldwin street is nearby - a cute little street with loads of restaurants which Penny visited all the time while she was doing her undergrad there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;king-st-east-st-lawrence-market:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;King St East &amp;amp; St. Lawrence Market&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;King St East is generally a nice area to walk around, with the St. Lawrence Market nearby. The market is a huge, with over 100 vendors selling groceries, souvenirs, bagels, you name it. Good place to shop for gifts for any loved ones back home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stlawrencemarket.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.stlawrencemarket.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pennyandalistair.github.io/img/st-lawrence.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fill-container-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(This image was originally posted to Flickr by Ian Muttoo at &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/20741443@N00/2700166150&#34;&gt;http://flickr.com/photos/20741443@N00/2700166150&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;art-gallery-of-ontario-ago:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Art Gallery of Ontario (AGO)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While obliged to mention the AGO, Penny is not terribly fond of it. For the longest time she was sure that Henry Moore was Canadian just because there are so many of his sculptures here. It&amp;rsquo;s too expensive to be honest ($20 admission), but it&amp;rsquo;s free on Wednesday and does have some decent postwar contemporary paintings, so give it a go if you are around then. Closed on Mondays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nightlife:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Nightlife&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nightlife in Toronto centers around &amp;ldquo;Clubland&amp;rdquo; - mainly along Adelaide St, south of Queen Street West. Penny recommends it, Alistair was too busy studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wikitravel.org/en/Toronto/Clubland&#34;&gt;http://wikitravel.org/en/Toronto/Clubland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-and-toronto-s-ethnic-neighbourhoods:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Food! And Toronto&amp;rsquo;s ethnic neighbourhoods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting things about Toronto is that - as opposed to being a &amp;ldquo;melting pot&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a mosaic of cultures. That means you end up with all sorts of villages - Little Italy, Koreatown, Greektown, Chinatown, Little Portugal, Little India - and while we should really work on coming up with better names for these places, all of them have amazing and authentic food representing their respective cultures. Go out and explore with your tastebuds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-restaurants:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Finding restaurants&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re talking about food, a good place for recommendations is www.blogto.com - also urban spoon tends to have reliable recommendations (as opposed to TripAdvisor&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;every restaurant is amazing&amp;rdquo; approach) - yelp is not bad either but you have to be careful for paid reviews (broken english, little detail).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-things-to-do:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Other things to do&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of more things to do in Toronto! I hope this page has given you some other ideas. You can also walk down Ossington avenue and say hi to the hipsters, comedy shows (Yuk yuks and the like), concerts, live music, visit the hockey hall of fame, tons more! The wiki has some good tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wikitravel.org/en/Toronto/&#34;&gt;http://wikitravel.org/en/Toronto/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outside-toronto:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Outside toronto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;niagara-falls-2-hours-away:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Niagara falls, 2 hours away&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Canadian side of Niagara falls is where it&amp;rsquo;s at! Really stunning to look at the power of such a massive waterfall. Niagara falls is not too bad of a drive, and there are buses which routinely go to Niagara falls from Toronto. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth a day trip (perhaps staying overnight for convenience). Highly recommend getting a ride on the &amp;ldquo;Lady of the Mist&amp;rdquo;, a boat which takes you close to the waterfall (you do get wet, but they give you complimentary ponchos). Aside from the falls/boat trip though, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much else to see here, except Casinos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;niagara-wine-region:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Niagara wine region&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The area between Toronto and Niagara falls (usually called Niagara-on-the-lake) is actually a pretty big producer of wine. We originally considered having our wedding at one of the wineries out here. It&amp;rsquo;s about a 90 minute drive from Toronto, depending on which Winery you visit.
We&amp;rsquo;re pretty far north, so expect to drink a lot of white (you&amp;rsquo;ll be hard pressed to find a full bodied red or anything like that). If you want to plan some visits, they have a &amp;ldquo;wine trail&amp;rdquo; map that you might find useful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://winecountryontario.ca/niagara-on-the-lake&#34;&gt;http://winecountryontario.ca/niagara-on-the-lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niagara-on-the-lake itself actually a town right along the Canada/US border and it is absolutely adorable. It&amp;rsquo;s about as close to a quaint Canadian town as you can get. If you are driving to Niagara falls and want a break from the big cities, we&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend stopping here for a casual stroll!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;algonquin-provincial-park:16bf5589f9e0be23236c59a1c0e40681&#34;&gt;Algonquin Provincial Park&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re really into nature, then look no further than the great Canadian north. And north it is indeed - about 3 hours from Toronto the Algonquin park is a bit far, but your reward is &amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave this picture here (yes, you can go Kayaking).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pennyandalistair.github.io/img/algonquin-provincial-park.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fill-container-width&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>